Bill Freyse Cartoons
Bill Freyse Cartoons
1960-1968
Freyse, Bill
5 linear ft.
Original cartoons, all but one from the comic strip Our Boarding House.
2652432
Biographical History
Bill Freyse (1898-1969) was an American cartoonist. His tenure on the established comic strip, Our Boarding House, ran from 1939 to 1969.
Born and raised in Detroit, Freyse began his newspaper career at a young age, working first as an editorial cartoonist for the Detroit Journal, then later as a staff artist for the Detroit Times. In 1939, Freyse signed on with NEA to continue Gene Ahern's immensely popular Our Boarding House comic strip starring Major Hoople. Ahern had left the strip a few years earlier, in 1936, to launch a knock-off version for King Features Syndicate, Room and Board starring Judge Puffle (Wood Cowan, Bela "Bill" Zaboly and others filled-in on Our Boarding House during the interim). Freyse's tenure on the strip was notable for the success with which he was able to maintain Ahern's identifiable artistic style while adding his own exceptional comic talents. Bill Freyse worked on Our Boarding House until his death in 1969. The strip continued with various artists until 1981.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Bill Freyse Cartoons collection contains original daily cartoons and 90 original Sunday cartoons from the comic strip Our Boarding House (1966-1967), and one item from an unidentified cartoon. Daily cartoons: blue pencil, pen and ink on illustration board, approx. 11 ½ x 13 ½ in. Sunday cartoons: blue pencil, pen and ink on illustration board, approx. 18 x 26 in.
Arrangement of the Collection
Daily and Sunday strips are housed separately in chronological order.
Related Material
See also the
Wood Cowan Papers
for additional material related to the Our Boarding House comic strip. has collections of over one hundred additional cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Freyse, Bill.; Newspaper Enterprise Association.; Our Boarding House (comic strip); Art -- Cartoonists; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Comic books, strips, etc. -- United States.; Cartoons (humorous images); Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Newspaper Enterprise Association, Inc., 1967-1969.
Unidentified cartoon, gift of Mary Sasaki, 2018.
Inventory
- Our Boarding House cartoons
  Click here for detailed inventory.
  - Daily cartoons
    - Daily cartoons, Mar 1966 - Sep 1966; 158 items (Box 1)
    - Daily cartoons, Oct 1966 - Apr 1967; 167 items (Box 2)
    - Daily cartoons, May 1967 - Dec 1967; 166 items (Box 3)
    - Daily cartoons, Jan 1968 - Jun 1968 (Box 4)
    - Daily cartoons, Jul 1968 - Dec 1968 (Box 5)
  - Sunday cartoons
    - Sunday cartoons, Jan 1966 - Dec 1967; 90 items (Oversize 1)
    - Sunday cartoons, 1968 (Oversize 2)
- Miscellaneous cartoons
  - "One order of revenge coming up", 18 Apr 1960 (Box 5)
    Gift of Mary Sasaki, 2018.